Guide to the New Yorkers at Work Oral History Collection OH.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Ida Klaus Description: Public Employment Relations Board; "Little Wagner Act", Mar 10, 1981; 103811 (Cassette 59A - 59B, Cd OH-01-379 / OH-01-380 / OH-01-381 / OH-01-382)
- Jerome Klied, Jul 17, 1980; 182942 (Cassette 60A, Cd OH-01-286 / OH-01-287)
- Joe Knowles & John Hanbury Description: The Newspaper Guild; Technological change at The New York Times, Sep 12, 1985; 103810 (Cd OH-01-092 / OH-01-093 / OH-01-094, Cassette 61A - 61B)
- Riki Kosut Description: United Office & Professional Workers; "Steno Queen" contests, 1940s, Nov 10, 1980; 103808 (Cassette 63A, Cd OH-01-095 / OH-01-096)
- Sam Kovenetsky Description:Department Store Workers, Local 1-S; Collective bargaining at Macy's, Nov 6, 1979; Dec 19, 1979; 103807 (Cd OH-01-401 / OH-01-402, Cassette 64A - 64B)
- Kitty Krupat Description: United Office Workers, District 65; clerical organizing, 1960s, undated; 103806 (Cd OH-01-403 / OH-01-404, Cassette 65A - 65C)
- Israel Kugler Description: Professional Staff Congress, undated; 103805 (Cassette 230A MISSING)
- Connie Kopelov Description: Coalition of Labor Union Women, Jan 29, 1981; 103809 (Cassette 62A - 62B)
- Celia Langert, Jan 23, 1989; 103803 (Cassette 153A, Cd OH-01-480)
- Jesse Langston Description: Waterfront Commission Port of NY; Visit to Brooklyn hiring hall, Jul 17, 1982; 103802 (Cd OH-01-097 / OH-01-098, Cassette 66A)
- Anita Lathan, Sep 24, 1999; 103801 (Cassette 256A - 256B)
- Oliver Leeds, Aug 9, 1983; 103800 (Cassette 147A - 147C, Cd OH-01-288 / OH-01-289 / OH-01-290)
- Sarah Leichter Description: United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union, Apr 26, 1979; Jun 7, 1979; Jun 21, 1979; 103799 (Box 1, Item Session: 33)
- Sam & Bessie Levine, Oct 3, 1980; 103798 (Cd OH-01-099 / OH-01-100, Cassette 68A - 68B)
- Barry Lipton Description: New York Newspaper Guild, Apr 2, 1997; 103797 (Cassette 238A - 238B, Cd OH-01-101 / OH-01-102 / OH-01-103)
- George Litsios, Jun 23, 1994; 103796 (Cassette 222A - 222C, Cd OH-01-291 / OH-01-292)
- David Livingston Description: District 65, Oct 25, 1979; 182943 (Cassette 69A - 69C, Cd OH-01-305 / OH-01-306 / OH-01-307)
- Ethel Loebman Description: May Day and Union Square, undated; 182944 (Cd OH-01-293)
- Cynthia Long Description: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 3, Oct 19, 1980; 103795 (Cd OH-01-108 / OH-01-109, Cassette 70A - 70B)
- Vincent Longhi Description: See Building Trades, Dec 11, 1993; 103794 (Cassette 216A - 216B, Cd OH-01-294 / OH-01-295)
- John Lopez, Nov 10, 1990; 103793 (Cassette 175A, Cd OH-01-104 / OH-01-105)
- Louis Lufkowitz, May 21, 1981; 103791 (Cd OH-01-106 / OH-01-107, Cassette 67A)
  Release form Lufkowitz
- John P. Lundergan, Apr 9, 1991; 182992 (Cassette 199A)
- James Lustig Description: includes Immigration, Hungary, Jun 15, 1981; 103792 (Cd OH-01-110, Cassette 71A)
- Bill Lynch Description: African-American Trade Unionist, undated; 103790 (Cd OH-01-111, Cassette 72A)
- Robert MacGregor Description: IBEW, Local 1049, Dec 21, 1988; 103788 (Cassette 179A - 179B)
- Sam Madell Description: International Longshoremen's Association; Waterfront rank and file, 1930s-1940s, Jul 16, 1980; 103787 (Cd OH-01-493 / OH-01-494 / OH-01-495, Cassette 73A - 73C)
- John Maguire, Jul 18, 1990; 103786 (Cassette 168A - 168B)
- Max Manes, Mar 2, 1989; 103785 (Cassette 154A - 154C)
- Julius Margolin, Jun, 15 2004; 182921 (Cd OH-01-112 / OH-01-113 / OH-01-114, Cassette 258A - 258B)
- Narciso Martas Description: Bakery, Confectionery & Tobacco Workers Union, Local 3, Jun 25, 1996; 103784 (Cd OH-01-115 / OH-01-116, Cassette 239A)
  Transcript available Box 4; Index available; Release form Yes
- Anne B. Martin, Sep 12, 1995; 103783 (Cassette 156A-B, Cd OH-01-405 / OH-01-406 / OH-01-407)
- George Martin, undated; 182989 (Cassette 200A)
- Jay Mazur Description: UNITE, undated; 182922 (Cd OH-01-117, Cassette 261A)
  A transcript of this interview can be found in the Asian Garment Workers in New York City Oral History Collection (OH 018).
- Moore McCormick, Jul 28, 1980; 182990 (Cassette 141A)
- George McDonald, Nov 29, 1994; 103782 (Cassette OH-01-450, Cassette 224A)
- Bob McElroy Description: National Maritime Union, Jul 14, 1980; 103781 (Cassette 74A - 74F)
- Bobbie McGee Description: Clerical Worker, Jul 20, 1981; 103780 (Cd OH-01-118 / OH-01-119, Cassette 75A)
- Bertha McGowan, Sep 1, 1981; 103779 (Cd OH-01-120 / OH-01-121, Cassette 143A)
- Brian McLaughlin, undated; 239180 (Cd OH-01-451)
  Transcript available Box 4
- Josie McMillian Description: NY Metro Area Postal Union, Jan 26, 1981; 103778 (Cassette 142A, Cd OH-01-122)
  Transcript available Box 4; Partial and Index available
- Joseph McPartlin, Apr 18, 1991; 182991 (Cassette 201A)
- Patricia Meckle, Sep 6, 1985; 182948 (Cd OH-01-408 / OH-01-409 / OH-01-410, Cassette 76A - 76C)
- George Meisler Description: Department Store Workers, organizing, 1930s, Dec 12, 1979; Dec 21, 1979; 103777 (Cd OH-01-411 / OH-01-412 / OH-01-413 / OH-01-414, Cassette 77A - 77D)
- Susan Metz & Merry Tucker, Aug 25, 1981; 103776 (Cassette 125A MISSING)
- Marcella Loring Michelson Description: Department Store Workers, Jun 18, 1980; 103775 (Cassette 79A, Cd OH-01-123)
- Clarina Michelson Description: Department Store Workers, organizing, 1930s, Oct 20, 1979; 103774 (Cassette 78A - 78B, Cd OH-01-296 / OH-01-297 / OH-01-298)
- William Michelson Description: Department Store Workers, 1930s, Jan 15, 1981; 103773 (Cassette 80A, Cd OH-01-124)
- Geraldine Miller Description: Domestic Workers; Migration, Southern Black, Jun 18, 1981; 103772 (Cassette 81A, Cd OH-01-125 / OH-01-126)
- Joyce Miller Description: Coalition of Labor Union Women, Jul 2, 1981; 103771 (Cd OH-01-361, Cassette 82A)
  Transcript available Box 4; Index available; Transcript available Box 4Release form Yes
- Saul Mills Description: CIO NYC Industrial Union Council, Apr 3, 1981; 182923 (Cassette 83A - 83B, Cd OH-01-127 / OH-01-128 / OH-01-129)
- Eleanor Mishnun Description: Women's Trade Union League; organizing, 1930s, Mar 22, 1985; May 3, 1985; May 22, 1985; 103769 (Cd OH-01-299 / OH-01-300 / OH-01-301 / OH-01-302 / OH-01-303 / OH-01-304, Cassette 84A - 84E)
  Electronic Transcript available, Release form Yes
- Walter Morris Description: Bedford Styvesant Restoration; Job discrimination, African-Americans, Oct 17, 1980; 103768 (Cd OH-01-130 /OH-01-131, Cassette 85A)
  Transcript available Box 4; Index available
- Mary Mullahey, Apr 20, 1980; 103767 (Cd OH-01-132 / OH-01-133, Cassette 86A)
- T.J. Murphy, May 21, 1997; 103766 (Cd OH-01-383, Cassette 240A)
  Transcript available Box 4; Index available; Release form
- Al Nash Description: Folder Empty, Apr 6, 1981; 103764 (Cd OH-01-362, Cassette 87A)
- Pauline Newman, Jan 19, 1980; 103763 (Cd OH-01-208, Cassette 227A - 227B)
- John Norman, undated; 182988 (Cassette 202A)
- Thomas Noschese Description: Painters Union; Technology, Oct 1, 1980; 103762 (Cassette 88A, Cd OH-01-415 / OH-01-416 / OH-01-417)
- Frank Novich National Maritime Union, Apr 5, 1981; 103761 (Cd OH-01-350 / OH-01-351, Cassette 89A - 89C)
- William Nuchow Description: International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 840; American Labor Party, Aug 6, 1985; 103760 (Cd OH-01-355, Cassette 90A - 90B)
- Thomas O'Brien Description: Lithographers' Union, Jul 11, 1984; 182919 (Cd OH-01-134, Cassette 33A)
- Ben Occhiogrosso Description: United Federation of Teachers, collective bargaining, 1960s, Jul 6, 1981; 103759 (Cd OH-01-135 / OH-01-136, Cassette 91A)
- Old Westbury Description: Oral histories done by students of SUNY (Andrucki, McPartlin, Martin, Lundergan, Benson, Brennan, Bauman, Livingston, Webster, Shaffer), undated; 103758 (Cassette 192A MISSING)
- John O'Neil, Jul 23, 1980; 103757 (Cassette 92A, Cd OH-01-418 / OH-01-419)
- Celia Orlansky Description: Garment Worker, Apr 30, 1981; Sep 23, 1981; 103756 (Cassette 93A - 93C, Cd OH-01-452 / OH-01-453)
- Francis Owens Description: Utility Worker's Union of America, undated; 182920 (Cd OH-01-137, Cassette 203A)
- Rita Palter Description: Leatherworker, Jan 17, 1991; 103754 (Cd OH-01-384 / OH-01-385, Cassette 170A - 170B)
- Elaine Paul, Jul 19, 1996; Jul 22, 1996; 103753 (Cassette 155A - 155C)
- Solly Pernick Description: IATSE, Local 1; stagehand, Jun 16, 1986; 103752 (Cd OH-01-138 / OH-01-139 / OH-01-140 / OH-01-141, Cassette 94A MISSING)
- Beatrice Pflaster Description: Newspaper Guild, Local 3, Jun 5, 1997; 103751 (Cassette 241A - 241B, Cd OH-01-142 / OH-01-143)
- Juan Pons & Carlos Rivera Description: Garment Workers, Jun 23, 1981; 103750 (Cd OH-01-363 / OH-01-364, Cassette 98A)
- Harold Pryor, Mar 16, 1989; 103749 (Cassette 211A - 211C)
- Clarence Reed Description: National Maritime Union; lumpen proletariat, Apr 27, 1986; 103747 (Cd OH-01-226 / OH-01-227 / OH-01-228, Cassette 95A - 95C)
- William Reiter Description: Sheetmetal Workers, Local 28, May 29, 1986; 103746 (Cd OH-01-144, Cassette 97A)
- Elliot Rief Description: AFSCME, District Council 37, Mar 11, 1987; 103745 (Cd OH-01-454 / OH-01-455 / OH-01-456 / OH-01-457, Cassette 96A - 96D)
- Carlos Rivera and Juan Pons Description: Garment Workers, Jun 23, 1981; 182986 (Cassette 98A, Cassette OH-01-363 / OH-01-364)
- Charles Rivers Description: Iron Worker, Photographer, Apr 29, 1991; 103744 (Cassette 190A - 190D, Cd OH-01-229 / OH-01-230 / OH-01-231 / OH-01-232)
- Al Robbins Description: National Maritime Union, Jun 30, 1980; 103743 (Cassette 99A - 99C, Cd OH-01-145 / OH-01-146 / OH-01-147)
- Lillian Roberts Description: AFSCME, District Council 37, Oct 27, 1981; 103742 (Cassette 100A, Cd OH-01-395 / OH-01-396 / OH-01-397 / OH-01-398 / OH-01-399)
- Sam Robert, Jan 12, 1990; 182987 (Cassette 159A - 159B, Cd OH-01-365 / OH-01-366)
- Camille Robinson-Gardner Description: Coalition of Labor Union Women, Jan 26, 1981; 103740 (Cassette 101A, Cd OH-01-311 / OH-01-312)
  Partial available; Transcript available Box 4; Release form Yes
- Cleveland Robinson Description: United Automobile Workers, District 65; African-American labor union leader, Oct 21, 1980; Oct 28, 1980; 103739 (Cassette 102A - 102C, Cd OH-01-308 / OH-01-309 / OH-01-310)
- Edgar Romney Description: UNITE, Local 2325, Apr 1, 2003; 182918 (Cd OH-01-152, Cassette 260A)
- Abe Rosen Description: United Store Workers, Apr 21, 1980; 103738 (Cassette 103A)
- Michael Rosen Description: Written Memoir, Jul 20, 1979; 103737 (Cassette 104A - 104B, Cd OH-01-153 / OH-01-154)
- Morris Rosenszweig, Jun 29, 1980; 103736 (Cassette 105A - 105B, Cd OH-01-313 / OH-01-314 / OH-01-315 / OH-01-316)
- William Ross Description: United Public Workers, Local 1, Mar 23, 1981; 103735 (Cd OH-01-458 / OH-01-459, Cassette 106A - 106B)
- Betty Bentz Rubin & Jay Rubin Description: HRW, Sep 6, 1988; 103733 (Box 1, Item Session: 155)
- Paul Rubin, undated; 182945 (Cassette 204A, Cd OH-01-317)
- Ernie Rymer Description: Prof. Engineering, Local 66, Jul 19, 1984; 103732 (Cassette 107A - 107B, Cd OH-01-155 / OH-01-156)
- George Schuck, undated; 182982
- Miriam (and Max) Schwadron, Apr 30, 1986; 103730 (Cd OH-01-170 / OH-01-171, Cassette 108A - 108C)
- Bea Schwartz Description: Department Store Workers, Local 3, May 7, 1980; May 17, 1980; 103729 (Cd OH-01-157 / OH-01-158, Cassette 109A - 109B)
- George Schwartz Description: National Maritime Union; McCarthyism, Jul 17, 1981; 103728 (Cd OH-01-348 / OH-01-349, Cassette 110A - 110B)
  Transcript available Box 5; Index available
- Thomas Scotland Description: I.B.E.W., Local 3, Jun 3, 1997; 103727 (Cd OH-01-159 / OH-01-160, Cassette 242A - 242B)
  Transcript available Box 5; Index available; Release form Yes
- Martin Segal, Mar 3, 1994; 182983 (Cassette 226A)
- Ted Schapiro, Jun 11, 1998; 182984 (Cassette 254A - 254B)
- Doris Shaffer, May 27, 1991; 182981 (Cassette 205A - 205C)
- John Sheehan Description: CLDL, Oct 19, 1990; 103726 (Cassette 178A)
- William Shelley Description: Newspapers Guild, Local 3, Apr 30, 1997; 103725 (Cd OH-01-161 / OH-01-162, Cassette 243A - 243B)
- Ken Sherbell Description: United Auto Workers, District 65; American Labor Party, Jun 25, 1980; Dec 12, 1981; 103724 (Cd OH-01-163 / OH-01-164 / OH-01-165, Cassette 111A - 111B)
- Rebecca Simonson Description: United Federation of Teachers, collective bargaining, Oct 29, 1980; Nov 10, 1980; 103723 (Cd OH-01-420 / OH-01-421 / OH-01-422 / OH-01-423 / OH-01-424, Cassette 112A - 112C)
- Shirley Simonson Description: Women in the Fire Department, Nov 19; 182985 (Cd OH-01-425, Cassette 208A)
- Lee Singer & Doris Emanuel Description: Office and Professional Employees International Union, Local 153, Oct 6, 1980; 103722 (Cd OH-01-166 / OH-01-167, Cassette 113A)
- Randall B. Smith Description: National Maritime Union, Nov 5, 1980; Dec 1, 1980; 103721 (Cd OH-01-318 / OH-01-319, Cassette 114A)
- Stanley Smith Description: National Maritime Union, Jul 16, 1981; 103720 (Cassette 115A, Cd OH-01-168 / OH-01-169)
- Lily Sokolofsky Description: Department Store Worker, Apr 21, 1980; 103719 (Cassette 116A, Cd OH-01-320)
- Jackie Stack Description: Chelsea Waterfront, Jun 11, 1981; 182946 (Cassette 185A, Cd OH-01-321)
- Joe Stack Description: National Maritime Union, Nov 5, 1981; 103718 (Cassette 118A - 118C, Cd OH-01-323 / OH-01-324 / OH-01-325 / OH-01-326 / OH-01-327 / OH-01-328)
- Monroe & Matilda Stein Description: Department Store Workers, Feb 11, 1979; 103717 (Cd OH-01-487 / OH-01-488, Cassette 117A - 117B, Cd OH-01-481 / OH-01-482)
- Leon Sverdlove Description: International Jewelry Workers Union; Diamond industry, Oct 23, 1979; 103716 (Cassette 120A - 120C, Cd OH-01-329 / OH-01-330 / OH-01-331 / OH-01-332 / OH-01-333 / OH-01-334)
  Transcript available Box 5; Release form
- Loretta Szeliga Description: Waitress; McCarthyism, Sep 11, 1981; 103715 (Cd OH-01-335 / OH-01-336 / OH-01-337 / OH-01-338 / OH-01-339 / OH-01-340, Cassette 119A - 119C)
- Hyman Teitelbaun, May 12, 1982; 103712 (Cd OH-01-172 / OH-01-173 / OH-01-174 / OH-01-175, Cassette 122A - 122B)
- David Tolan Description: Sealand Corporation; waterfront technology, Sep 1, 1980; 103711 (Cd OH-01-343 / OH-01-344, Cassette 123A)
  Transcript available Box 5
- Ida Torres Description: United Store Workers, Jun 24, 1980; 103710 (Cassette 124A, Cd OH-01-176 / OH-01-177)
- Merry Tucker Description: United Federation of Teachers; NYC fiscal crisis, 1970s, Part 1, Aug 2, 1981; cuid14388; 103709 (Cassette MISSING 125A)
- Merry Tucker Description: United Federation of Teachers; NYC fiscal crisis, 1970s, Part 2, Aug 2, 1981; cuid14389 (Cassette 125B)
- Merry Tucker Description: United Federation of Teachers; NYC fiscal crisis, 1970s, Part 3, Aug 2, 1981; cuid14390 (Cassette 125C)
- Allan Tumolillo, Jul 11, 1980; 103708 (Cassette 126A, Cd OH-01-178 / OH-01-179)
- Helen Turner, Jul 22, 1980; 103707 (Cd OH-01-341 / OH-01-342, Cassette 128A - 128B)
- United Store Workers, Local 3, Oct 16, 1979; 182934 (Cassette 130A, Cd OH-01-180 / OH-01-181)
- UPI, Local 107, undated; 182980 (Cassette 129A)
- Evelyn Virgo & Anna Rouse, Jul 23, 1981; 103706 (Cd OH-01-149 / OH-01-150 / OH-01-151, Cassette 131A - 131B)
- Caesar Viruet Description: Newspaper Guild, Local 3, May 28, 1997; 103705 (Cassette 244A - 244B, Cd OH-01-460 / OH-01-461)
- Judith Vladeck, Oct 15, 2004; 182998 (Cd OH-01-476, Cassette 262A - 262D)
  Scope and Content Note
  Interview by Roger Horowitz.
- Emagene Walker Description: Coalition of Labor Union Women; Migration southern Blacks, World War II, Nov 27, 1981; 103703 (Cassette 132A, Cd OH-01-182)
  Release form Yes*amended
- Pearl Walker Description: Women in the Fire Department, Dec 11, 1990; 182977 (Cd OH-01-462, Cassette 207A)
- Richard Walsh Description: IATSE, Nov 4, 1987; 103702 (Cassette 149A - 149B, Cd OH-01-496 / OH-01-497)
- Keri Webster, Apr 17, 1991; 182978 (Cassette 206A)
- Philip Weightman Description: AFL-CIO Committee on Political Education; Voting rights for African-Americans, Apr 11, 1981; 103701 (Cassette 133A - 133C, Cd OH-01-345 / OH-01-346 / OH-01-347)
- Grace Weiner Description: AFSCME, District 37, Aug 21, 1981; 103700 (Cd OH-01-183, Cassette 136A)
- Louis Weinstock Description: Painters Union; McCarthyism, Dec 16, 1980; 103699 (Cd OH-01-184 / OH-01-185 / OH-01-186, Cassette 135A - 135B)
- Everett Wiltshire Description: Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers Int'l Union, Local 3, Nov 12, 1996; 103698 (Cassette 245A - 245B, Cd OH-01-187 / OH-01-188)
- Conrad Woelfel, Mar 27, 1980; 103697 (Cassette 134A - 134B, Cd OH-01-189 / OH-01-190)
- Ruth Young, Aug 29, 1985; 182979 (Cd OH-01-463 / OH-01-464, Cassette 217A - 217B)
  Transcript available box 5
- Vincent Young, Aug 4, 1983; 103696 (Cassette 148A)
- Sol Zalon Description: National Maritime Union; McCarthyism, May 29, 1980; 103695 (Cassette 139A - 139C, Cd OH-01-387 / OH-01-388 / OH-01-389 / OH-01-390 / OH-01-391)
- Helen Zalph Description: Typographical Union; technology., Sep 6, 1981; 103694 (Cassette 138A)
- Irving Zeidman Description: Local 2155, Feb 14, 1985; 103693 (Cassette 140A - 140C, Cd OH-01-426 / OH-01-427 / OH-01-428 / OH-01-429 / OH-01-430)
- Belle Zeller Description: Professional Staff Congress, Jan 8, 1986; Jan 9, 1986; Jan 14, 1986; 103692 (Cassette 160A - 160C, Cd OH-01-191 / OH-01-192 / OH-01-193 / OH-01-194 / OH-01-195)
  Related Materials
  Zeller was interviewed by Irwin Yellowitz, a professor of labor history at the City University of New York and fellow Professional Staff Congress member. More information about Yellowitz and the Professional Staff Congress is available in the Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Records and the Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Oral History Collection. These collections are also held by Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives; call number WAG 009 and OH 061 respectively.
- Transcripts (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5)
- Access CDs OH-01-444 to OH-01-497 (Box 21)